[Killua] The King's self-harm,
the existence of a third party…
We're still nowhere close to figuring out
what really happened.
[Morel] It's time.
One minute left to go.
[singer singing in Japanese]
[singer singing in English]
CHARGE X AND X INVADE
[lock clicking]
[ticking]
[imperceptible]
[narrator] Two minutes
before Morel's call to arms…
two men leapt from a giant creature
and began their long descent
to the Republic of East Gorteau,
which expanded below.
[narrator] Pitou was the first
to notice it.
"just because."
Pitou's hunch was vague.
[Neferpitou] Something's coming.
[narrator] But seconds later,
faint suspicions became certainty.
[Neferpitou] The enemy.
that even Pitou's extraordinary senses
were unable to detect them at all.
Now battle ready, this certainty
was a result of feral instincts
left over from Pitou's animal origin.
[gasps]
Pitou's En…
disappeared?
[Morel] Ten more seconds to go.
Nine…
Eight…
Seven…
[narrator] As Morel counted down
to the impending attack,
[Morel] Six…
Five…
Three…
Two…
[gasps]
[Morel] One!
Go!
[Neferpitou] Where'd they go?
in the face of a menace to the King
A far greater threat
than this countless rain of dragons
[narrator] When Pitou uses
this Nen ability
in order to fight at full strength,
it takes less than a tenth of a second
from activation to attack.
BAD MOVE
No, it's true.
Think about it.
When people are near death,
time seems to slow down,
It's a similar principle.
In fact, I consider this phenomenon
even more credible,
You can even obtain personal information
that could only be known
by the other person,
SPIRIT ECHOES
This temporal discrepancy often occurs
when truly powerful warriors clash.
The secret behind that old fart's power?
There are several possibilities.
Fool! We aren't equals.
He's always gotten the best of me.
What?
you had better look out for…
[narrator] Netero's sequential movements
appeared to be deliberate, fluid.
At least, that's how it looked
from Pitou's perspective.
between the activation
of Pitou's Nen ability
and the subsequent attack.
Pitou was able to capture
Netero's movements by sight,
[wind blowing]
[narrator] Netero, 46 years old, winter.
Sensing that he had reached
the upper limits
of his physical and martial arts skills,
he pondered and reflected,
and he realized that he was grateful.
for making him into the man he had become,
and he wanted to show his gratitude
in his own unique way.
At first, this sequence took
five to six seconds to complete.
On the first day, the 10,000 punches
took him more than 18 hours.
Once finished,
he'd fall asleep on the spot.
He would wake the next day
and repeat the process.
[birds chirping]
[bird screeching]
After two years, he noticed a change.
[breathing heavily]
[narrator] Even after the 10,000 punches,
the sun had not yet set.
[narrator] This gave him
more time to pray.
[floor creaking]
[students murmuring]
[man 1] Who the hell is this guy?
Why is he dressed that way?
[man 2] I'd like to see him try, Master.
[murmurs continue]
[narrator] When Netero came down
from the mountains,
it seemed that his fists
had left sound behind them in their wake.
[crack echoing]
[man 4] It's like he disappeared.
[assistant] The sound came so much later.
Uh, sir?
The… [weeping]
Bodhisattva Guanyin.
Will you defend your dojo?
[instructor] This dojo is yours.
But please, please make me your pupil.
[narrator] It was the birth of a monster.
Yeah, sure.
If you treat me to a real nice meal.
[static crackling]
[narrator] This turn of events
took place over six decades ago.
[Neferpitou] Considering
where his hands stopped,
that attack came from
an impossible direction. How?
I would appreciate it if you would
disappear far into the distance.
[Neferpitou] Damn.
I'm nowhere near where I started.
[Shaiapouf] Sire!
[gasps] Pouf!
He can't hear me.
He's too worried about the King.
Dr. Blythe!
[narrator] Normally, that's an ability
that's useless for anything
but medical treatment.
You see, Dr. Blythe cannot move
from where it's activated,
[narrator] That restriction was
just enough to keep Pitou in the fight.
Faster!
[gasps]
MIDNIGHT
[yawns]
Hmm?
[grunts]
[narrator] There, where they had hoped
they would encounter no one at all,
[closing theme music playing]
[upbeat music playing]
[Gon] Next time, Monster and Monster.
[singer singing in Japanese]